Ander **Granado Masid**

■ ander@protonmail.com | 😭 walkonthebyteside.com | 🖸 ander94lakx | 🛅 ander-granado-masid

Summary _

Computer engineer by vocation with a self-taught spirit. I have worked as a software developer and cybersecurity consultant in different types of projects. In my free time, I like to learn about hacking and programming. I am currently focused on the world of computer security, especially in pentesting and malware analysis. Open to new opportunities, especially remote ones.

Experience ____

Cybersecurity Consultant

Bilbao, Spain (Remote)

DEVOTEAM CYBERTRUST (BECLEVER SOLUTIONS)

Dec. 2021 - Present

IAM Consultant: Consulting and Implementation of Customer and Workforce IAM solutions like Okta and Auth0

Software Engineer

Vitoria-Gasteiz, Spain

SEGULA TECHNOLOGIES SPAIN

Aug. 2018 - Apr. 2021

- Industrial environments simulation applications with .NET (C#), WPF, OPC UA
- Data Acquisition Systems (DAQ) for industrial processes with Python, MySQL, Beckhoff Industrial PCs
- Application development for european R&D projects with .NET (C#), ASP.NET, OpenAPI

Junior Game Programmer

Madrid, Spain

MOON FACTORY STUDIOS

Mar. 2016 - Oct. 2016

· Rolling BOB (PlayStation 4 videogame) developed with Unreal Engine 4 and C++. Gameplay programming (with some architecture and UI programming)

Education

Master's Degree in Computer Security

Online

UNIVERSIDAD INTERNACIONAL DE LA RIOJA (UNIR)

2020-2021

Bachelor's Degree in computer Engineering in Management and Information Systems

Vitoria-Gasteiz, Spain

UNIVERSITY OF THE BASQUE COUNTRY (UPV/EHU)

2012-2018

Skills

Programming C# (.NET, WPF, ASP.NET, API development), Python, C++ (Visual C++, Unreal Engine 4), Java (Kotlin), Git, SVN, Perforce

DB / Sys

MySQL, SQL Server, Linux, Windows Server

Hacking

Kali Linux, nmap, metasploit (Ethical Hacking) / IDA, Ghidra, x64dbg (Malware/Reversing) / Autopsy, FTK Imager (Forensics)

IAM

Okta, Auth0, OAuht2.0, OIDC, SAML

Publications

Application of the SAMA methodology to Ryuk malware

Academic Paper

JOURNAL OF COMPUTER VIROLOGY AND HACKING TECHNIQUES

 Paper focuses on demonstrating the use of a malware analysis methodology by applying modern malware analysis techniques in a real and complex malware sample

Walk on the Byte Side

Technical Bloa

AUTHOR

Since 2024

· Personal blog focused on cybersecurity and programming with a highly technical approach, where I share projects and ideas that I work on or that come to mind

Certifications

- 2023 Okta Certified Developer Customer Identity Cloud (Auth0), Okta
- 2022 Okta Certified Developer Workforce Identity Cloud, Okta
- 2022 Okta Certified Administrator, Okta
- 2021 Internal Auditor ISO 27001:2013 Certified Qualification, TÜV Rheinland

Languages _

English B2
Spanish Native
Basque B2